<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dikshya Mohanty</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dikshya Mohanty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/education/</guid>
      <description>University of North Carolina, Charlotte, USA  August 2018 - December 2019
Masters in Data Science and Business Analytics
Relevant Courses: Business Intelligence, Deep Learning &amp;amp; Neural Networks, Big Data, Database Systems, Advanced Business Intelligence, Applied Machine Learning, Visual Analytics, Graduate Econometrics
GPA: 3.75 / 4.0
 Indira Gandhi Institute of Technology, Odisha, India  August 2012 - May 2016
Bachelor’s of Technology in Computer Science
GPA: 3.7 / 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Summary</title>
      <link>/professionalsummary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/professionalsummary/</guid>
      <description>Incoming Data Science Intern : Amazon Graduate Teaching Assistant : University of North Carolina, Charlotte  Duration: January 2019 - Continuing
 Appointed as the TA for Business Intelligence Analytics Class by Dr. SungJung Park (Belk College of Business, UNCC) and Big Data for Competitive Advantage Class by Dr. Gabriel Terejanu (College of Computing and Informatics, UNCC). My responsibilities include assisting professors in preparing the course plan and schedule, grading assignments and exams, mentoring students and conducting lab classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Teradata Data Challenge Text Analytics of Scientific literature into a causal network A semi-automatic text extraction and grouping of theoretical constructs and variables
(1) Extracting performance indicators as DVs, (2) Grouping DVs by stakeholder group (and subcategories), (3) Identifying and extracting predictors, (4) Grouping predictors, (5) Linking all into a causal network using Visuals.
Irony Detection in Twitter Data The task of the project was to build a supervised Machine learning model to detect irony in tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Teradata Data Challenge  Date: January, 2019
 Text Analytics of Scientific literature into a causal network  Date: October, 2018
A semi-automatic text extraction and grouping of theoretical constructs and variables
(1) Extracting performance indicators as DVs, (2) Grouping DVs by stakeholder group (and subcategories), (3) Identifying and extracting predictors, (4) Grouping predictors, (5) Linking all into a causal network using Visuals.
 Irony Detection in Twitter Data  Date: August, 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Network Tutorial</title>
      <link>/posts/neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>An Artificial Neural Network (ANN) is an information processing paradigm that is inspired by the way biological nervous systems, such as the brain, process information. The key element of this paradigm is the novel structure of the information processing system. It is composed of a large number of highly interconnected processing elements (neurons) working in unison to solve specific problems. ANNs, like people, learn by example. An ANN is configured for a specific application, such as pattern recognition or data classification, through a learning process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Forest Tutorial</title>
      <link>/posts/randomforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/randomforest/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial explains the random forest algorithm in simple terms and elaborates on how it works by including various examples. It includes a step by step guide for running the random forest algorithm in R. In addition, it highlights the explanation of parameters used in “randomForest” R package. Random Forest is one of the most widely used machine learning algorithms for classification. It can also be used for regression models (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>An incoming Data Scientist Intern at Amazon! Data Science Professional with 2+ years of experience in project work and freelance jobs. Skilled in machine learning, statistics, problem solving, and programming.
Skills and Technical Summary:  Statistics and Visualization Softwares: SAS, R Studio, Tableau, SPSS, Anaconda, PostGre, Matlab, STATA
 Programming Languages: Python, SQL, SAS, R, JavaScript, Java, Scala, Perl
 Technical Skills: Machine Learning and AI, Deep Learning and Neural Networks, Statistics, Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, Cross-Section and Time Series Analysis, AWS</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>