<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Summary on Dikshya Mohanty</title>
    <link>/professionalsummary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Summary on Dikshya Mohanty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/professionalsummary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Teaching Assistant</title>
      <link>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps1/</guid>
      <description> University of North Carolina, Charlotte January 2019 - Continuing
 Appointed as the TA for Business Intelligence Analytics Class by Dr. SungJung Park (Belk College of Business, UNCC) and Big Data for Competitive Advantage Class by Dr. Gabriel Terejanu (College of Computing and Informatics, UNCC). My responsibilities include assisting professors in preparing the course plan and schedule, grading assignments and exams, mentoring students and conducting lab classes.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Research Assistant</title>
      <link>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps2/</guid>
      <description> University of North Carolina, Charlotte October 2018 - Continuing
 Working with Dr. Victor Chen (Belk College of Business, UNCC) and Dr. Wlodek Zadrozny (College of Computing and Informatics, UNCC). Primary focus of research is building a Causality map between various dependent and independent variables.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Developer</title>
      <link>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps3/</guid>
      <description>Tata Consultancy Services, Pune, India July 2016 - July 2018
● Participated in architectural, design, and product sessions ● Developed innovative solutions based on product requirements and business challenges in both Python and R ● Researched and applied new technologies and best practices in Machine Learning including PyTorch, TensorFlow, NLTK, Spacy, Sklearn, Numpy, Scikit ● Worked in Unsupervised Natural Language Processing, Image Processing, Document Classification, Predictive Modeling ● Managed data over PostgreSQL, MongoDB and Elasticsearch</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Intern</title>
      <link>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/professionalsummary/2019-05-03-ps4/</guid>
      <description> Indian Institute of Technology May 2015 - October 2015
 Developed and improved Summarization algorithms in Python, aiming to implement them on the Standard Datasets and improving the then accuracy Worked on extracting, categorizing and extracting and predicting user-related information  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>